Hikage Dojo
Pull yourself together!
What is your name?!
N-Naka Hikage.
That's right. And what is your brother's name?!
My brother's name is... Tatsu... Hikage...
Correct.
As inheritors of the 300-year-old
Hikage style of martial arts,
we siblings must continue to maintain
a strong sense of self-discipline!
Yes. I shall do my best, Dear Brother.
As long as you understand.
I've let down my dear brother once again.
Oh, man... I'm so glad that mishap
didn't scar my Naka's adorable face!
We will now commence the Ogiso Private
High School Katsuda Grand Triple Festival!
Katsuda Festival
Ogiso Private High School
The theme for this year's inter-class
competition will be "cops and robbers"!
Episode 9: You and the Cultural Stage.
It starts at 2 PM!
Which class will seize a glorious victory?!
Mascot Café
Class 1-A
Crepes
Are you sure this is all right?
Student Council Office
This year, you'll be the only cop,
and all the other students will be robbers,
according to these special rules.
Isn't that too much of a handicap?
Not a problem. The real issue...
Enrollment Application Form
Applicant
Yuki Yokoya
Female
is this "Yuki Yokoya."
She transferred in as
Hitoyoshi Yokoya's cousin,
but much of her background remains an enigma.
1-A... The same class as my dear Naka.
She'll be participating in today's competition,
as well. We'll need to keep an eye on her.
Indeed. There is a possibility that she could
be one of Hikage's enemies out for revenge.
In which case...
I will investigate her myself
during my patrol.
For Tatsu to personally take action...
As we suspected, this Yuki Yokoya
may be no mere student.
By the way, what is Naka's class
doing for the event?
Um, I believe it was...
Welcome to the Mascot Café!
Dear customers, feel free to select
whichever headwear you like.
You see, I don't think...
my brother likes me very much.
Your brother? Do you mean President Hikage?
Yes. My brother is very results-oriented—
a real perfectionist.
But as his younger sister,
all I am is small and weak.
Is that why you want to win?
Yes! Winning may be difficult, but if I can
show him that I can accomplish things, too,
I was thinking he might finally see me
as worthy... if only a little.
And also...
N-Never mind!
It seems like Hikage has a hard time
talking in front of Ms. Yuki...
Don't worry. Thanks to you, we were able to
get the info we needed about the competition.
Right! Winning at cops and robbers
is all about athletic ability.
And each class has to choose
three participants.
Katsuda's Sauce
Mr. Katsuda's Sauce?!
Yo. I'm Katsuda-Man.
Hey, is that you, Taiga?!
You're gonna compete like that?!
Why, of course I am!
Katsuda-Man is invincible!
Kurokawa...
Just you watch! The golden trio of Yuki,
Hikage, and I will blow your socks off!
We'll beat the crap out of
that president and then some!
Come to think of it, I don't remember
ever actually seeing Hikage in gym class.
That's because... I don't want to
stand out too much...
Katsuda's Sauce
Oh, I'm not as fast as my brother,
but I'm really good at running, so...
I'll do my best to be useful!
Do not worry.
When our prospects of winning seemed dark,
you parted the clouds with a ray of hope.
I will give it my all, as well.
Let us combine forces and beat the crap out
of the student council president together.
Yuki...
Y-You're right.
I'll never beat the crap out of my brother
if I give up before I try!
Yes! That's the spirit!
Welcome! The menu is right over...
Pissed
How dare you beguile my dear Naka,
have her use such crude language,
and scheme to drive a wedge
between us siblings!
Yuki Yokoya... I won't forget this affront!
Katsuda Festival
Taiga, are you seriously going to play
cops and robbers as Katsuda-Man?
Yep.
The Katsuda Festival is all about
Katsuda's Sauce reigning supreme!
I'll stand out on TV and become
the No. 1 local mascot!
Katsuda's Sauce
What a stupid idea...
Oh... That's right. There'll be people
from the TV station here.
I wonder if Ms. Yuki will be okay
with being filmed...
Ms. Yuki, um...
Ooh! I spy Big Brother and Ms. Yuki!
I was looking everywhere for you guys!
Kobachin told me you've been slacking off.
How delinquent of you!
We were in charge of the café all morning,
so we're off duty for the afternoon.
Ms. Yuki has the competition, too.
So I can't catch Ms. Yuki & Co.
at the café anymore?
Harrumph!
Harrumph
Sorry, Riko!
You'll have to make do with Kobachi this year.
Don't lift me up!
Oh, I see. Kobachin's just
lonely from being left out.
Stop patting my head, Taiga!
That's it! I'm going back to work!
Sorry, Kobachi.
You guys really are close.
Yes.
Um...
D-Do you have friends, Yuki?
Friends...
Oh, um, I-I didn't mean to make it sound
like you don't have any!
Um, you see, the one who doesn't
have friends here... is me. So...
If you don't mind...
would you... be friends... with me?
Certainly. Let us...
be friends.
Ms. Yuki! Riko said she wants to go take
a look at the cultural festival with us.
Friends...
Understood. I will join you.
How about you, Hikage?
Do you want to come, too?
Um, I still have things I need to check, so...
She looked pretty excited about something.
What were you guys talking about?
Master Hitoyoshi...
What does it mean to be friends with someone?
Huh?
Friends with Yuki...
Friends...
If Yuki finds out about the real me,
we can still be friends, right?
To make sure of that...
I need to win this competition
and show Yuki how useful I can be!
The meeting room of the Katsuda
Festival Executive Committee...
I'm a little far away, but...
If I concentrate, I should be able
to hear them at this distance.
Competition... rules?
Oh, no...
It won't be long before today's main event,
the inter-class cops and robbers
competition, kicks off for real!
Introducing our very special guest: Nazca!
Hello, Katsuda citizens!
Are you all enjoying the taste of the sauce?
This is Nazca!
The rules are simple!
If President Hikage captures all the
robbers and throws them into prison,
the cops win!
But if even one robber gets away,
the robbers win!
By the way, a robber can escape from prison
if they're touched by a free robber
from the same class!
Oh, my. Doesn't this put the robbers
at quite the advantage?
That's right!
There's also an additional rule which
Nazca will be announcing. Take it away!
Okay.
As a new rule...
all contestants will be asked to wear
whatever they wore for their class store
while participating.
I'm so sorry... If I'd managed to
get hold of this information sooner,
we might have been able to work around it.
I'll be fine, but the two of you...
Uh, I was already planning on
participating like this, remember?
A friend is...
Ms. Hikage. You have nothing to apologize for.
A friend is someone who lends a hand
when their friend is in trouble.
Let us work together to defeat your brother.
Yuki...
Besides...
It'll be harder to move in,
but it lets you hide your face.
We wouldn't want another assassin
like Grace catching sight of you.
Master Hitoyoshi mentioned that it would be
undesirable for my face to appear on TV.
Katsuda's Sauce
Katsuda-Man is here!
This mascot onesie actually works in my favor.
Now, is everyone ready?!
The time limit is 15 minutes!
Which class will make Student
Council President Hikage eat dirt?!
My little sister is too cute!
Hoppity hop.
Smiley smile.
Is something the matter?
I'm sorry... If I look at my brother
right now, I might freeze in place...
Did she just reject me?
Why is she hiding behind another?
My dear Naka!
That's... Yuki Yokoya!
I see. Yuki Yokoya...
You are the root of all evil!
I will not let your sins go unpunished!
The president sure is fired up this year!
Indeed.
The president may be at a disadvantage, but...
I can't shake this feeling of anxiety.
Ms. Yuki! Go get 'em!
All right, robbers, please disperse!
Why does Tatsu look so angry?
Who knows?
Uh, excuse me, Enome siblings.
You know you're heading toward the cop, right?
It's not against the rules
to deliberately get caught, is it?
Sorry, but as members of the student council,
we can't be getting ourselves injured.
We'll be supporting the president
from inside the prison.
So hurry up and begin!
Huh? Oh, okay...
W-Well, then, let's begin the match.
Man, he's fast!
Oh, this is unexpected!
It's a superhuman power play!
What am I looking at? A human bulldozer?!
Don't ask me!
There's nothing that can stop him now!
The robbers are losing
their will to fight, as well!
My goodness, what do we have here?
We're just three minutes in,
and there are only three robbers left!
All three are from Class 1-A's Mascot Café!
Yes! Fight the good fight, Mr. Katsuda's Sauce!
Nazca is looking at me!
She's expecting great things from me!
That's right. Right now, I'm Katsuda-Man.
I'll be taking you down first!
Because I'm...
Katsuda-Man!
You'll pay a heavy price
for beguiling my dear Naka,
Yuki Yokoya!
Y-Yuki, I think we should split up here.
No... I believe we are already too late.
Yuki!
What's this intense aura I feel?!
In that case...
I'll shut you down, here and now!
What should I do? I need to escape... But...
Certainly. Let us... be friends.
This smoke... Could it be...
Wh-What the?! What just happened?!
It's an illusion!
One moment, a huge smokescreen appeared,
and the next, the bunny rabbit
went flying into the air instead!
Did Ms. Hikage do that just now?
A friend is...
someone you can fool around
and do stupid stuff with, maybe?
Stupid stuff...
Well, that's just an example.
I think there are all
different kinds of friendships.
They often called my friends and me
"the three stooges" back then, you see.
Can you not be friends if you haven't
been acquainted for a long time already?
I don't think that's the case, but...
You see, I went through some
rough patches in the past,
and those two were the only ones
who didn't give up on me.
They really changed my life.
I can't thank them enough.
I'm hoping that if they need my help one day,
I'll be able to do the same for them.
That's what friendship means to me.
Would you... be friends... with me?!
What friendship means to me...
My dear Naka!
Don't push yourself too much, Naka.
It's just a cultural festival, you know?
No...
This is important to me.
And with that bunny toss,
we're at the ten-minute mark!
The president has completely frozen!
What in the world has happened?!
Is this one of those standoffs between strong
warriors where whoever moves first loses?!
I can't... believe I did that...
to my dear Naka...
He looks like he's in shock to me.
with my own hands...
And more worryingly,
Ms. Yuki looks distracted somehow.
My dear Naka...
Winning the competition is my top priority.
To do that, I just have to evade him
for two more minutes.
The problem is...
doing so in such a way
that I don't appear on camera.
And, more pressingly...
Takoyaki
bringing myself to evade a man to whom
the scent of Katsuda's Sauce clings.
Did he do this on purpose to make
it harder for me to escape?
I can't let my guard down!
That girl sure is giving Tatsu
a run for his money, though.
Yes! Yuki is amazing!
Y-Yuki... Please do your best!
The silence has been broken!
The president and the mysterious wolf
are equally matched!
Just who is this person?!
This woman isn't giving an inch!
Takoyaki... Okonomiyaki... Yakisoba...
I'm hungry.
I don't know what you're plotting
to do with Naka, but...
The blood ties between us Hikage siblings
are not so easily broken by the likes of you!
I wonder what's for dinner tonight...
But what I understand least is...
how you can casually hang around my
sister as though you're already friends!
To be her friend is to be
someone very special to her.
And just what do you know about Naka?
Nothing! You don't know anything
about my sister's pain and suffering!
It's only a matter of time until
you plunge her into deep despair!
Someone...
What does it mean to be friends with someone?
special...
I'll separate you before that happens!
Huh? She threw Tatsu?!
Holy crap...
The president's been tossed on the ground
like a sack of potatoes!
Just who could this mysterious wolf be?!
Why, you...
You're just going to run away?!
You craven coward!
Twenty seconds left!
Is the wolf going for a prison break?
Ms. Yuki...!
Ms. Naka.
I answered you earlier without truly
understanding what friendship is.
But now, I understand a little better.
Because I have someone special to me, as well.
If I can become someone like that to you,
then that is what I want to be.
So, allow me to now ask you:
will you be my friend?
The match is over!
What an intense match,
all the way to the final whistle!
Huh? So what just happened?
Our class won, right?
She touched Hikage to save her.
Ms. Yuki probably knew that...
But aren't they both in prison now?
Ms. Yuki was in prison when
the whistle blew, wasn't she?
Could it be that...
Ms. Yuki didn't really understand the rules?
The winner is President Hikage!
Katsuda Festival
The student council, class 2-E,
has won their second year in a row!
And now, let's move on
to the competitors' interview!
Have fun!
That's our cue, guys!
Right!
N-Not good!
If Ms. Yuki gets interviewed in her
current state, she'll be eaten alive!
President! Mysterious Wolf!
Your thoughts on the competition, please!
The camera...
Master Hitoyoshi mentioned that it would be
undesirable for my face to appear on TV.
Katsuda's Sauce
I-I have to help Yuki!
That pink smokescreen again!
Why, you! What did you make my sister...
Eek! A muscular gorilla?!
Damn it! Where did that woman go?!
Where's Ms. Yuki?
I can't see anything with all this smoke.
Just what is going on?
Yokoya!
Katsuda's Sauce
Yuki is Katsuda-Man.
What?!
For now, let's get her away from here.
Okay! Riko, give us a hand!
Roger dodger!
What? What's going on?
I'm sorry. It's my fault we lost.
No, it was all due to my own misunderstanding.
At the time...
all I could think of was saving you.
I wanted to be liked by you, too.
Let us share the responsibility,
just as we share our friendship.
Okay!
Naka!
Dear Brother...
You must be exhausted. Let's head home.
Y-Yes, sir!
This vixen... Given half a chance, she's
already ingratiating herself to my sister again!
I can't take her lightly!
I'll let this slide for now.
But in future, Yuki Yokoya, I'll show no mercy
to those like you who lead others astray!
If you'll excuse us!
Ms. Naka.
I'll see you again at school.
Yes... See you at school!
Ms. Yuki!
Master Hitoyoshi.
You're not going to the show?
I am content to watch from here.
Ms. Yuki... Um, are you okay?
Huh?
I thought you might be feeling down,
losing the cops and robbers game and all.
Though I should be feeling disappointment,
I'm left feeling something else.
For some time now—
ever since I learned of the Katsuda Festival—
I've felt this fluttery feeling,
like I can't settle down.
It's something a little different from what
I feel when I'm with you, Master Hitoyoshi.
And when the match was over,
the first thing I felt was...
You don't want the festival to end, right?
From where I'm standing, you looked
like you were having a whole lot of fun.
You got so excited that you
even misunderstood the rules.
I see.
So this whole time... I was having fun.
It's going to end, isn't it...
The cultural festival...
It was our first cultural festival, after all.
We lost this year,
but there's always next year.
Next year?
We should really come up
with a thorough plan next time,
and win against the
president's class once and for all!
I've never thought as far ahead
as next year before.
I'd always lived as though
I could be killed at any moment.
But here, my former reality
feels as distant as a dream.
In this world, there is a tomorrow,
and a future with infinite possibilities.
I can think about things like tonight's dinner
and make arrangements to see others again.
Come to think of it, I'm hungry.
I want to eat tonkatsu for dinner,
but how about you, Ms. Yuki?
Yes...
I feel the same way.